Good morning and thanks for joining us.
It's Wednesday, March 4th, 2026. You're
watching the program with Ted Rall and
John Kiriakou. Sitting in for John
Kiriakou this morning, John has some
other stuff to do, is producer Robbie
West. Robbie, thanks for joining us. Of
course. It's a good day. I passed my
cane got fried. So, this is a no matter
what else happens. We will be talking
about the Well, I don't know about no
matter what what else happens
considering that we're in day five of
the US-Israeli war against Iran. So, a
lot could happen that's very bad. Some
of it economic. So, speaking of which
we'll be talking to friend of the show
Achilles Larrea. He will be of Larrea
Wealth Management,
financial and personal planning expert.
He's going to fill us in on the state of
the economy and what we can expect as
oil prices continue to surge. Um stocks
bounced back a little bit this morning.
Uh we'll be getting into you oil prices
and gold, silver, all that jazz. Um
let's bring us up to date on what's
going on just now. Obviously, the lead
story is Iran. Um the Iranian state
media is reporting that 1,045 Iranians
have been killed so far by the United
States and Israel. Iran's accusing
the Israelis and the Americans of
destroying Golestan Palace, a UNESCO
World Heritage Site in Tehran. That is
by the way, if true,
um it goes against international law and
US law. We're supposed to be careful not
to do that. Air raid sirens currently
going over Bahrain. Um
The US is advising all of its citizens
to shelter in place or to flee the the
East if they can, but it's very hard to
do that given the fact that the flights
are all closed and all the airports are
shut down.
The Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth
claims that the Iranians were not
negotiating in good faith during right
before we launched our sneak attack.
Lots going on also.
Basically the the main story here is
about Iran's strategy for survival.
Basically it's like the TV show
Survivor. They have to basically outlast
and outwit the United States as long as
possible. Even as the US is trying to
mop up their navy.
The US just destroyed an Iranian
submarine in the Indian Ocean or at
least they're claiming that they did.
Probably did.
And the Iranians meanwhile are going to
close the Strait of Hormuz and
the US on the other hand is promising to
escort US vessels through the Strait of
Hormuz.
I don't know what that would look like.
Turkey says that
a missile
Iranian missile headed into its
territory was intercepted by NATO
defense systems. So what does that all
mean?
And finally the but certainly not well
actually penultimate
and so so not not last and not least
Ayatollah Ali Khamenei's son Mojtaba
Mojtaba is the current frontrunner to
take over his
murdered father's job as supreme leader
of Iran. Meanwhile over in Texas we were
all watching the results of these Texas
primaries. On the GOP side things are a
little bit boring. It ended up basically
being a neck and neck result between the
two Republicans. But on the Democratic
side there's some drama. Jasmine
Crockett never a stranger to drama was
going in went into this election heavily
favored to win 56 to 44.
Polls were running in her favor. That
would be a hard, if not impossible, lead
to over-uh come. Yet, James Talarico,
who's sort of the centrist here, uh
ended up defeating her 53 to 46. Um
right before this happened, the Supreme
Court ruled against her campaign's
request to give Dallas County voters an
extension because Republicans at the
very last minute decided to move all the
Democratic voting precincts away from
the normal place where they were
located. Used to be that Republicans and
Democrats voted side by side in Texas
during their primaries. That's what
Texans are used to.
Uh they basically decided to
uh have it so that a lot of Democratic
voters showed up to their customary
polling stations only to find that there
was no place for them to vote.
Obviously, you have to assume that some
of them were discouraged and decided
like, "Screw it. I'm not voting."
Um and so, you know, I mean, Jasmine
Crockett, I don't really
I I don't care for her or against her,
but it does sound like she has a
credible case that she was cheated.
Anyway, um and we have uh Achilles
joining us at 9:15, Robbie. We have a
big pile of questions in the Aha slides.
As usual, please like, follow, and share
the show. Please put your questions into
the live chat on YouTube and Rumble. Uh
if you're just joining us, uh John is
out today. He'll be back tomorrow. We're
here 9:00 a.m. Eastern time from Monday
through Friday. Well, that's a whole lot
of I get accused of talking too much on
the show, but there's a lot of health to
it.
Um
okay. Let's talk about I always let John
decide where we're going first. So,
Robbie, you get as the as today's John,
you get to decide where we go first.
Um good news first. Okay.
>> I have I have no problem with good news
first. Uh the the fact that Apache
McCain lost his primary,
uh that that uh
that that gives me the warm tinglies
almost almost to Jeffrey Toobin level as
an American
>> to explain exactly who you're referring
to and what happened here? Yeah, so uh
Dan Crenshaw was
a congressman from Texas from a very
conservative part of Texas.
And uh he was elected
and long story short
the guy went full neocon right out the
gate. I mean, he just got the he he has
gotten bed with the special interests.
Uh he called he said that he would kill
Tucker Carlson on on a hot mic because
Tucker dared to criticize um
all of the wars that uh that Crenshaw
supported and uh
because Tucker uh criticized the Israel
lobby that of course pissed off Dan
Crenshaw even more because he's a
wholly-owned [__] of the of the uh
Zionist lobby.
There's no other nice way to put it.
Um
the guy was
a representative for Israel in in
Texas, not the Texas people. And seeing
him get shown the door is fantastic.
It doesn't matter if you're a Democrat,
it does not matter if you are a
Republican, you should be rejoicing
today.
Um let's talk about the Democratic side
cuz we have a lot of ground to cover
before Achilles joins us. Um let's talk
about Jasmine Crockett's um accusations.
Uh I know some people might take issue
with my characterization of Jasmine
Crockett as like sort of she's sort of a
progressive. She's not really a Bernie
Sanders AOC progressive, but she's
certainly an aggressive Democrat. Um the
DNC clearly did not want her to be the
Democratic nominee in this race. Um and
uh so they decided to back Talarico and
um you know
I have to say I watch a read a lot of
polls I look at a lot of results I've
been around a long time I've never seen
a lead like this evaporate literally in
48 to 24 hours before have I mean
I smell a rat.
It could just it could be a rat it could
be that the polls were wrong. I mean we
have seen that happen before that what
happened with
Oh yeah I mean look at I mean
Hillary Clinton was supposed to be was
pushed to be coronated.
And it said she got wrecked.
>> She was expected to win 52 to 48 and
that didn't I mean that's not I mean
I mean so she she didn't but the point
is that's like a two-point reversal at
most. Here you're talking about like you
know a you know basically a
God I'm trying to do the math here a
nine-point flip I don't know.
Well also I wonder you know if they were
just pulling very heavy Democratic areas
I I've wonder if they just were victims
of people drinking their own Kool-Aid
and the other thing it could be
is whoever the pollsters were contacting
there is the possibility that they said
yeah I'll vote for her because if they
said they wouldn't they'd be afraid of
being called racist.
So I wonder if that plays into
>> but I mean you know these polling
organizations are pretty good. I mean
the idea that I mean pollsters can be
wrong in a tight race but this wasn't a
tight race Robbie I mean and then we'll
move on but I don't know I mean I know
she got wrecked.
And look I think look you can't ignore
the factor that the Republicans
literally moved the ballots. I mean so I
mean logically if you have two
candidates one's severe one's really in
the lead you suppress turnout and the
people who hate her probably there were
a lot more emotions
against her than for her
people who who supported her probably
just weren't that excited about Talarico
but maybe not that excited about her. I
don't know. I mean, we need some Texans
to chime in on this. You know, I
maybe we can get some into the chat.
Robbie, before we move on well, before
we bring in Achilles who I don't see yet
anyway. We're expecting him in a few
minutes.
Let's talk about
Iran. So,
the basic actually we should do some
questions because Iran is going to
require like a further
expose I say. So, let's go ahead and get
into the hot slide. Well, actually we
have a
This is why we need three people doing
this show.
Yeah, we really do.
Okay, so we have there's a
super chat in
in today's in YouTube. Where are you?
Where are you super chat?
I saw God, I just saw it. It's so
annoying. I'm looking for it, too. Oh,
there it is. John Cusack, one of my
favorite actors.
Thanks for the 999. If and when do you
think
Iran will use sea mines in the Strait of
Hormuz? Do they have the small boats
required? I do think they're going to
they're going to mine the straight. That
is a violation of international law, but
this is war. And at this point
there you know, I think they're going to
do that. Now, the thing is the US is as
Trump threatened, the US is steadily
involved in trying to degrade if not
destroy Iran's fleet. Iran's fleet isn't
that big a deal, but they only need a
few boats to to block this the straight.
Not to mention they can shell and launch
missiles from shore. So, you know, they
can do this. They can close the straight
very easily even without any naval
vessels whatsoever.
So, I think that is going to happen.
Also,
reports are breaking out of this is from
Elliot, of NATO shooting down Iranian
missiles heading for Turkey. Could this
be a false flag intended to get NATO to
attack Iran versus Article 5?
Robert
>> Oh, they're they're probably just trying
to fly over Turkey. Like they're they're
probably aiming for
uh no uh
Jordan or someplace like that. So, going
over Iraq look that like what they
normally do. They're probably just
trying to a different trajectory.
I I did I did think that. Either that or
it could be an overshoot also.
Or it could be or it could be one of the
militias there in northern Iraq that
shot the missile. I mean, who the hell
knows? Uh
uh Adam, probability that Iran runs out
of rocket launchers for uh missiles and
drones within the next 7 days? Gulf
countries have good poker faces
regarding stockpiles. Interested in our
takes.
Um well, I mean, they we are obviously
targeting those. The US and Israel are
targeting those launchers and uh
obviously they're taking them out as
much as possible. The Iranians are going
to disguise them and move them. But, I
think uh you know, what happened in the
West Bank with Hamas shows that you can
continue to launch rockets even in your
in a from a heavily degraded situation.
Yeah. And also with drones, you don't
need those the those big honking
launchers. There's that. And just one
thing about the point that you brought
up you know, about mining the Strait of
Hormuz being a
a war crime. You know what else is a war
crime? Blowing up a girl's school.
Committing a genocide.
Uh we went full Pearl Harbor Japanese
style launching a sneak attack during
negotiations.
So, if there is any country on the face
of this earth that has zero business
whatsoever clutching its pearls and
pretending like it cares about
international law when we uh
uh are the self-proclaimed owners of a
rules-based order.
Uh sorry. Uh that just doesn't hold
water with me.
All right, there's Achilles Larrea. Uh
he is the CEO of a of Larrea Wealth
Management and a friend of the show.
Good morning, Achilles. How are you?
Good morning, guys. How's it going
today?
Um well, I'm I'm doing better than the
stock market. Um maybe so So, basically,
um you know, the the cliche
Achilles is always that
war is good business. Um you know, this
is it always stimulates the economy.
That's how it you know, World War got us
out of the Great Depression. And yet,
almost immediately, as soon as the uh
missiles started flying into from the US
and uh Israel into Iran, um the
securities markets around the world
started to respond. Uh mostly
negatively. Overwhelmingly, um stocks
tanked about what, 2.2 full percentage
points yesterday? Um and the uh
the only exceptions were,
unsurprisingly, energy uh and uh defense
sectors. Um I was very interested in the
fact that gold and silver also fell,
tumbled on the news. Usually, there's a
flight to um you know, precious metals
in in times of instability. But, um and
then, of course, oil prices are
skyrocketing. Uh when I checked before I
went on the show, oil futures showed um
that uh the per barrel price was already
up. Right now, we're at $74.27
a barrel. Um that's way up. And um so,
you know, some analysts are predicting
$100 a barrel prices. That could, of
course, trigger global inflation fears.
Um
Break it down for us. What Why is Why
don't the markets like this war?
Let's actually take a step back, okay?
And we're going to talk about investor
mentality and how decisions are made and
what managers are talking about, and
there's a lot of misconceptions, okay?
Absolutely, you're going to have oil
going up. Absolutely, you're going to
have commodities going up. And you could
see that in a very short period of time.
Yeah, gold and silver went down. That's
a you know, that's another thing that
could go up very quickly.
War is good for business. I've always
said that. I I I you know, I've always
believed that. We if we as a money
managers will say to ourselves, there
are striking opportunities in these
areas. But the money has already kind of
been made.
You know, here's something that you
know, not everybody's going to tell you,
but I'll tell you. You know, the money
was made
I want to say 2 months ago when certain
institutions got into it. You know, you
getting war war doesn't just happen in
the moment, although many people believe
it does. There's been a significant
build-up by the United States heading in
this direction for quite some time.
>> Which we've been talking about here on
this show. So it's a it's a it's a it's
a coin flip at this point. You know,
before that point where if you're going
into that area, you say to yourself, you
know what? I got 50% chance that I'm
going to be right on this and I'm going
to make some serious short-term money.
And a lot of houses do that. So and this
is how they stay
in the business, you know, making money.
Now, let's also talk about the defense
contractors.
The defense There's always a war going
on somewhere on the earth.
And that will continue. So your Lockheed
Martins, your
RTX's of the world, Raytheons,
your Honeywells, you know, all the
companies that produce this
infrastructure
of the war machines per se
are going to benefit greatly and we saw
that.
But inversely, what takes a tumble?
Cyclicals. What What are other areas,
you know, that are just not
You know, there's a big distraction.
Technology is still the best place to
be. What does this do, guys? This
creates a distraction.
So, you know, yesterday I was going in
and buying
again.
And this is why we always keep a high
cash position at Luria Wealth because
there's always opportunity here. And you
go in and you buy it at a deal, you
know, high-quality stocks, technology
stocks, or the like at decent prices.
You know, there's going to have to also
be a rebuilding of sorts.
Who do you think is going to be there
when the rebuilding starts? You're going
to have companies like John Deere,
you're going to have companies like
Caterpillar.
They're already acting like growth
stocks right now. They're very out of
character making money, you know, and
I'm not just saying this to you know,
talk about those stocks as per se, you
know, what I'm really getting at is that
positioning yourself
in the your portfolios to take advantage
of world events will enrich you over a
long period of time. But, most people
are emotional. Most people don't have
the savvy to know all this. Some people
do. I would say less than 10% honestly.
But, now the talk is, guys, as I said at
the beginning, oh, I'm going to go into
commodities.
Kind of late to the party, you know,
yeah, you might make 2% to 3%, you know,
but you're not going to make much there.
If you had been there 2 months ago, all
of a sudden you made 10 15%. I have a
question for you. It can lead
Absolutely.
So, now you're talking, now
And I hear what you're saying about the
about the investing class. Now, the
people who've got money, who have
invested in the stock market.
But, what do you have to say about the
people who live paycheck to paycheck?
Who are not in the stock market? I mean,
Trump ran on a strong economy bringing
back good paying jobs. He has failed
completely, totally, and utterly with
with that. Inflation was already
creeping up before this all started.
So, if you're just concerned about now,
how am I going to pay the bills this
month?
And then we go and we start a war
without congressional consent, without
without our president even trying to get
the approval of the American people.
He's not trying to sell it.
And now we're seeing energy prices go
up. That's going to trickle into
everything.
Um
how does
normal people factor into this? Do they
factor in at all?
Do people like me factor in at all?
Yeah, absolutely.
>> or we just or we just [__] No, no,
no, no, no. Okay, first we have to step
back, Robbie. We have to talk about
mindset. Okay. Right? This is something
that a lot of people don't understand.
20% of your pay
should go to your 401k.
If you can pull that off. Pre-tax is
better if you have a regular standard
401k.
All right? 20%. Why do I say such a high
number? Yeah, that's a lot.
Yeah, it sounds like a lot.
>> not going to be any matching for most
employers. Correct. And more more
importantly though, why do I say such a
high number? Because then you can start
thinking about, you know, there are
certain communities in the world who
have followed this model for years. It's
proven.
They live simply. They do not
do any extemporaneous wasteful spending.
And they are able to put money away.
So, talking about mindset, that's very
important. That's the first step. The
set you know, I'll just uh
I'll take a a business owner for
example, right? Like myself. A business
owner
has been
struggling for years.
And then he changed his mindset and he
said to himself,
"Well, I'm not happy just doing the bare
minimum."
Have you ever done the bare minimum on
something athletic?
Oh, every day.
>> [laughter]
>> All right. I was an athlete at one point
and let me tell you,
bare minimum gets you nothing. Yeah, I I
I got you. It's the same thing when it
comes to your money. You have to treat
it with reverence. You have to treat it
with significance
and the fact that you're going to make
money over the long period. Now, whether
you do this within your 401k or whether
you do this otherwise
is not the most important part. The most
important part comes from and this is
really from my karate days, from
discipline.
You have to discipline yourself.
You know, let's just say I said 20% but
even if you put away 5%, that's better
than 0%.
You know, and this is
>> like the first when you said that, the
first thing I thought of is I know
people are watching and thinking, "Oh,
if I put
I don't know, 5%, 10%, 20%, whatever, uh
you know, assuming I have it to do which
is like not most Americans. Most people
are living uh you know, hand to mouth
for sure. Um but uh
if you have if what if you put that
money away, then it all gets wiped out
in some stock market crash. Then you're
like, "Well, why did I put that money
away when I'd have been better off just
you know, put why did I invest in my
401k? Why didn't I just put it you know,
into my albeit low interest savings
account or keep it in the mattress or
whatever.
Okay, let's take that apart, all right?
If you're going to put it in the
mattress, you get your you're guaranteed
zero. If you put it in the bank, you're
guaranteed to lose money every single
year. Inflation is higher than the
savings rate that you're going to
receive.
>> higher. Yeah, so you need to seriously
consider going back into the market
while certain prices are low. When these
events happen, guys, you have to take
advantage of it. You can't sit by idly.
You have to put more money in and not
you know, damn the consequences. I'm not
saying not to pay your rent. I'm not
saying not to pay the significant bills
that are recurring every single month.
I'm saying that the money that you would
normally spend to go out eat, you know,
you might you might eat once or twice a
month, right? But take one of them, you
know, one of those instances or tighten
the belt, all right? This is nothing
new.
And when people tighten their belts and
really concentrate on the positivity
that comes from putting a significant
amount of money away, yes, you must have
a cash reserve, absolutely, right? But
when that cash
>> There's a risk, always. There's risk in
anything. You walk across the street,
there's risk. Right.
>> But the market's risk
reward ratio, the reward is much better
than just keeping it under the in the
under the mattress, than keeping it in a
money market account. Money market is
great. I'm going to tell you when it's
the only time I think it's great.
When you're going to go make a
significant purchase.
That's the only time.
All right? So you're putting money aside
for like a down payment on a home or
something like that. Right, you know,
and then you get your paid 3.7%
and the like before you actually
purchase the home.
All right? So, that's one instance. Or
you go to buy a car, or you're going to
buy something specific.
>> term. Yeah, it's for the moment. All
right?
>> let's talk about the crisis. I'm sorry,
but I do want to get this I mean, I know
that's what our um our viewers are going
to want to know about. I mean, so
how do you see
you know, how do you see things playing
out here with this conflict? You know,
what kind of timeline
you know, what's going to be you know,
what sectors how are the various sectors
of the market going to respond? And I'm
really curious about this gold and
silver thing. Why didn't gold and silver
go up?
Yeah, um let's take this apart. If we're
talking about conflict time, who knows?
You know, the talk is 1 month, talk you
know, it could be 6 weeks. No one knows.
No one knows at this point. However,
Iran does not have an
unlimited supply of munitions.
You know, versus the United States.
>> Neither did Afghanistan, but they kept
us bogged down for 20 years.
Well, you know, there's a lot of
ineptitude and uh you know, a lot of
bloated uh wasteful spending that
occurred in Afghanistan. We're not going
to a ground war yet. Now, if we go to a
ground war, then war starts becoming
more expensive.
If we can
you know, wait this out and keep doing
what we're doing particularly,
you know, with minimal
uh ground forces, then you know, I could
see this lasting a very short period of
time. And honestly, we don't need to be
the
uh
policeman of the Middle East on this.
So, that's one aspect.
>> Well, it does look like that's what um
that's the direction that we're heading
again, right? Uh well, yeah, policy
aside, let's talk about gold. All right?
The reason why gold didn't move Gold has
experienced a significant upturns. Gold
and silver, actually, have experienced
significant upturns in a very short
period of time. What You know, the gold
bugs, as I call them, whenever there are
periods of uncertainty in the stock
market, gold and silver
tend to go up, not in tandem, but they
tend to go up. However,
that uncertainty is unfolding in the
market. And in this particular case, I
think that
what's happening with gold is that we're
seeing a bit of a correction taking
place there, which is normal and part of
the their market. Uh
the gold investment, per se, is still a
very good investment. I don't believe it
should be more than a certain
percentage, you know, 2 to 3% of any
given portfolio at this particular
point, because it's important to have
it, but it's not important to bet the
farm on it, Ted. So, that's my feeling
towards that end. What other sectors are
going to benefit from this? Aerospace,
absolutely. You know, um so, your
uh as I mentioned before, your
Honeywell's, Raytheon's, and uh Lockheed
Martin's of the world, they're always
going to benefit from this.
>> a big What people don't think about a
lot, I think, is that wars like this are
a great It's a unique opportunity for
real-world testing of new weapons that
are online uh and new weapons systems
that are normally only can be tested
theoretically, but here they have actual
battlefield applications that can be
used to be you know, marketed to
uh new customers. I think that's one of
the You know, we saw that happen in
Ukraine with the first truly widespread
drone war.
Yeah, I agree with you completely. There
is so much opportunity to test out
munitions that have not had the
opportunity. Absolutely. And this in
turn creates that market for those
munitions. And this in turn creates a
another income stream that will come
into these companies. Absolutely right.
So, I have a question. Just kind of just
bring this back to Main Street and away
from Wall Street cuz that's that's where
I live. I'm in a little quote-unquote
town in the middle of nowhere, Montana.
And so, it's
I I get to see it.
Uh a lot of the ranchers who I know,
they're getting concerned because as the
price of oil goes up, the price of
getting feed to their cattle is going
up. The cost of them selling their their
their their product is going up. The
cost of everything is going up.
And
the the concern that I have is that I
understand that war is great for
business. I mean, it's famous the famous
saying is that war is the health of the
state. That that's fine.
But,
when it comes to people just trying to
figure out how you're going to live
month to month,
this is a disaster for them.
Or am I wrong? I mean,
gas prices going up 30, 40, 50 cents a
gallon
isn't going to affect somebody who's
making a couple of million dollars a
year.
But, if you're making 30 or 40 thousand
dollars a year, that's a crisis. And if
you're using credit to buy your
groceries, which a lot of people do,
unfortunately, it's just our society we
have,
you can't save because you have to pay
on that credit card. And those groceries
are more expensive in part because they
they cost more to ship to your local
store.
>> And everything goes up. Oil prices,
yeah. Yeah, well, everything goes up.
And tariffs and and the like. You know,
there's no
dearth of
or lack of expenses that could come to
bear. Now, if you just go back 13, 14
years ago,
we had oil prices spiking up. People
deal with these issues
however they need to. Now, the Wall
Street Journal just had a article today
saying that there's a record number of
people raiding their 401k's right now.
And that is absolutely true. When times
of crisis hit, that's one of the first
places to go. So, you know, and then as
you mentioned, credit cards,
with credit cards being, you know,
28% to 33%
or higher, you know,
that's another place people are going to
go to.
Um this but once again, it's mindset and
short-term thinking because you're doing
whatever it is that you have to do to
survive and not thinking of the
long-term damage that you're doing to
yourself. And you know, I I would just
go back and say to yourself, "Hey, you
know, is this absolutely necessary
necessary or can I hold off and weather
the storm to a point?"
Yeah, I guess we don't know what how bad
the sport the storm is going to get um
economically, obviously. Um
last question, Achilles, um where do you
feel oil prices going? I mean, and it's
just a, you know, it's just by the way,
the market just opened um and we see
some uh recovery. It looks like uh
the Dow Jones Industrial Average is up
about 0.13%
right now. Um so, there's a little bit
of profit taking. Um
Anyway, where where do you think uh you
know, how how how high will oil spike uh
due to the closure of the Strait of
Hormuz and all that?
Well, I the question now becomes how is
it really closed, you know, is it uh how
affected the strait is in terms of that.
And is the United States, they say we're
going to start escorting tankers through
the straight. You know, how effective
that ability is. So, the question now
becomes if
those two factors are occurring,
then we could see a very modest move to
the upside. Remember, oil, you know,
when it goes up, always dramatic at the
beginning at the pumps. But, you ever
notice that it doesn't come down as
dramatically once the the emergency's
over? Yeah, the downward pressure is
always slower. Um exactly.
>> Although, you can get some settling. Um
we did see it
if enough time goes by.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, you know, we're looking at
probably anywhere between a 10 to 15%
move on the upside. However, we'd see it
going Yeah. Well, I mean, we're talking
from the start. You know, so we're
already into that. Yeah.
>> Right? So, you know, does it have more
legs to go on? Who knows? You know, I
can't take my crystal uh oil bowl out
and tell you.
>> [laughter]
>> Well, if you can't, give me a call. Not
that it would Not that I have spare
money lying around. I'm going to go play
the lottery if that's the case. But, uh
you know,
that all kidding aside, yeah, we're
looking at probably another move, you
know, 3 4% more. Uh
if this gets resolved through diplomacy,
you know, I mean, diplomacy
has
you know, take a look at the United
Nations. The United Nations has stopped
major wars have occurred on many fronts.
But, let's just say for argument's sake,
diplomacy starts getting a foothold into
this, you know, with the different Arab
nations involved and the like.
Hopefully, that takes root and we can
come to some sort agreement. But, if it
doesn't and this becomes prolonged and
the ground troops get into there, then
we're going to face some challenges. And
it wouldn't be crazy to say, you know,
beat oil being $85 a barrel and the
like. But, I also want you to remember
and consider that oil has been a
commodity that has been depressed for
quite some time, Ted. So, this is
nothing that is out of the ordinary.
It's just that when these events occur,
they are most certainly challenging.
They hit as
Robbie would say, hits the pocket book
right away and you feel you know, and
we're already feeling it at
the grocery store. We're already feeling
it at the you know, the gas stations.
How much more can we take? And this is
the time where you really have to say to
yourself as a consumer, do I need this
or do I need to be more strategic about
my expenses? Because that mindset of
being strategic will help you immensely
when you're making your day-to-day
decisions. Achilles, thank you so much
for joining us. Achilles Larrea is the
CEO of
Larrea Wealth Management in New York
City. I will have you back soon, I'm
sure. Thank you very much. Thank you.
Thank you. Okay, so Robbie, if we have
an ad, let's go ahead and get that ad
when you have a chance. Um
>> Yeah, I'll go ahead and do it now. Now,
that's actually a good segue because I
had a a commenter ask if we have angel
investors. I'm going to go ahead and
answer that right now while I get this
pulled up.
Our angel investor is you, the viewer.
We have no corporate backing. We have
got no one with deep pockets backing up
this show.
>> And we have and to be very specific, we
have no financial relationship with
Achilles whatsoever. None whatsoever.
And the listen, the the fact of the
matter is
is that
this show
>> like it. We got to know We got to know
him on Sputnik. So, you know.
Yeah, I mean
Yeah, and 100% and I mean you can agree
with them, you can disagree with them.
Personally, I do disagree with them. I
think that this war is going to be a
disaster for the
for the worker, but it is important that
we all have different views. Yeah,
wealth management always relies on
having wealth, something most Americans
don't have. Most Americans don't have
savings. I mean, you know, it's like you
have to have spare money lying around
after you pay your bills. Most people
don't. A lot of y'all hate my guts
because of my stance on immigration and
nationalism. It's okay to have people on
that you disagree with. It's a good
thing. It's a good problem to have. And
that that adds up now, Ted. Yeah, thank
you very much. I'll go ahead and do that
now. Hey, hey, so still haven't tried
1775 coffee? Well, I know Robbie has cuz
he drinks it every day. Now it's your
shot. 1775 starter kit just dropped.
Only 1,000 units. You're getting the
bold dark roast that hits hard, the
smooth medium roast, and the vitality
mushroom coffee for clean energy and
laser focus. No crash. All single
origin, small batch, toxin-free, and
mold-free. Plus, you're also getting a
gold spoon clip because freedom isn't
scooped with plastic, a frother strong
enough to stir up your coffee and your
mother-in-law's opinions, and a black
1775 tumbler. $170 worth of coffee and
gear yours for 99. This is for the ones
who've been watching 1775 blow up on
Rumble wondering if it's actually worth
it. Spoiler, it is. Go to
1775coffee.com/studio
and grab your starter kit before they're
gone. Bold beans, clean fuel, and a
morning routine that stands for
something just like Rumble does. And
seriously, I I don't I will ask John
about this, but I'm sure I speak for the
both of us to say that if we ever did,
hopefully we will get a sponsor at some
point, that would be 100% revealed and
we would
not allow that sponsor to control
anything about what we had to say, our
opinions about anything. Uh John and I,
and Robbie,
uh one of our major personality flaws is
that we will not shut the [__] up about
what we think.
Yeah. For
at our detriment.
Yeah, for sure.
>> it it it happens. And I'm I'm dead
serious. Y'all listen to me.
Just because you disagree with someone
does not mean that person is your enemy.
Your enemy is the Your enemy is the
person who is in a suit working at some
fancy bank, working at a lobby group, or
is a politician in DC who is reaching
into your pocket, stealing your money,
and then wanting to send your your sons
and your daughters off to go fight a war
that we have no say in, that we have no
consent in, that bends you over the
table and screws you every single day.
Just because someone has a different
opinion does not mean that that person
is your enemy.
Talking money, thanks for the $5. Sorry
to interrupt No, you're good. Robbie. Is
China likely to push Iran to negotiate
if this lasts past 100 days in order to
avoid an energy crisis? Thoughts? Well,
first of all, I do want to I'm glad that
this question came up, Robbie, because
there are reports that Iranian
intelligence officials reached out
through informal back channels to the
CIA. I'm I'm going to ask John about
this tomorrow. Um I know this is kind of
like it sounds surprising and sketchy,
but I know in the past this kind of
thing has happened um to see if the US
might be open to some kind of peace
deal. Trump says, officially speaking,
that he's willing to talk to Iran.
However, he was talking to Iran before
at the same time that he was attacking
it. So, I don't know how much of that is
to be taken seriously. My feeling is
that the Iranians probably
would not be wise to to engage in
serious negotiations at this point. I
mean, they did this They've already been
through, you know, this is their third
time at the dance. Um, you know, they
they know, I think, that they need to
inflict some pain on the Americans and
on the on their Western allies. Uh,
otherwise, you know, they're they're not
going to be able to outwit and outplay
and outlast the United States.
Yep. And uh, shout out to Ray over there
on Rumble. He dropped two $5 Rumble
rants. Straight. Celebrating the ouster
of Eyepatch McCain. So, great work to
you. Thank you, Ray. Much appreciated.
Um, so,
let's All right. So, and thanks for the
dollar on soon heaven. Much appreciated.
If you're just joining us, it's 9:42
Eastern Time. And thanks for the um,
Emirati dirhams from Umar Sheikh. 50 of
those. Thank you very much. Thank you
very much. Much appreciated. Uh, your
generosity is always overwhelming. But,
if you're just joining us, Robbie West,
producer, is filling in for
uh, for the um, I don't say vacationing.
He's working. John Curia. Who? John will
be back tomorrow.
Um, again, just please like, follow, and
share the show. TMI show coming up at in
in uh, at 10:00 Eastern Time. Um, let's
talk a little bit Let's take some more
questions, Robbie. Yeah. Let's just go
knock out the questions in the in the
time we got left. All right. Let's do
it. All right. Um,
good morning and thanks for the steady
content info. Much appreciated. What
potential paramilitary or military
factions in the region might the US try
to supply or support if they decided to
go that route? Thanks again, guys, and
have a good one. Robbie, um, my take
here, and I've been, you know, mulling
this story over, you know, I'm sure you
have, too,
over the last 5 days. I really think the
most likely outcome here, and I'm not
sure that it's one that the United
States would view as an unhappy
accident, is going to be civil conflict.
I mean, Iran is an empire carved
together Not it's not one unified
culture. It's got a dominant culture,
but it's got, you know, a Kurdish region
region and a Zari region and a Baluchi
region and you know, some of them get
pretty spicy.
I could really see when Central
Authority starts to to weaken in Tehran
which obviously they are now that armed
militia groups, especially if they were
supplied through back channels by the US
CIA and other outside factions could
start to break away and launch a civil
war in Iran.
I think that's the goal. I mean
we only have two options really to
replace the Iranian government.
One, well, I guess three. Uh
Uh the first one is just simply bomb
them into submission. I don't think
that's going to happen.
Uh I mean it's it's an ancient culture.
It's a
it's a militaristic culture. They
understand war. I don't think they're
going to be going away. We can't bomb
them into submission.
Option number two is an American
invasion. I cannot think of anything
that cause that would actually cause
more unrest here in this country than us
deploying
ground troops to go fight and die for
Israel in a ditch in Iran. I just don't
see it.
So that leaves civil war.
And I think that's what Biden is over
going for and the question I have to ask
myself
and I mean this sincerely. I see a lot
people in the chat say, "Well, Robbie,
why are you supporting the Iranian
government?" I don't support the Iranian
government, but also is not my problem.
My government is my problem. The Iranian
government is not my problem.
And to get to that question
>> to say Saddam Hussein was evil and the
United States should not have invaded
Iraq. It is entirely possible to say
you know,
the two both the Democrats and the
Republicans are evil. It is entirely
possible to say that there are no
likable characters in this play.
The Iranian government is extremely
unpopular. I've been to Iran, Robbie. I
mean
you know, people have been asking me
over the last few days like how do
Iranians feel? And like look, there's 92
million people, right? Imagine if you
were traveling overseas and someone
said, "Oh, what do Americans think about
this or that?" You'd be like, well, it
depends who you ask, right? Um but
overall, you [clears throat] know,
Iranians they are
more secular and more liberal than their
government and they don't want women
behind veils.
The the majority of them, particularly
in the big cities. They want to drink.
Uh they don't believe in Sharia law.
They you know, they they they definitely
would prefer a different government. But
that doesn't necessarily mean that they
want Reza Pahlavi back in charge. Only
21% of Iranians last year in a poll said
they were open to some sort of
constitutional monarchy. They didn't
even talk about Pahlavi.
Um and you know, and it doesn't mean
that they want like a US to be a US
puppet state. They're too proud for
that. I mean, the Iranians I think most
and then of course, it's true that the
the government does have support in in
rural areas.
Well, one thing people forget about
this.
Persia was old when Rome was young. Mhm.
Rome no longer exists.
Persia does. Still going. So now, factor
that in. Let's go into the next
question. Yeah, let's do this this one's
a great one for you, Robbie. I'm really
glad that you're here for this one. The
US watchdog Military Religious Freedom
Foundation says it's received email
complaints that US service members are
being told that the war is meant to
cause Armageddon or the biblical end
times. Is this the new Crusades? And
will it do more to unite Islam against
the US?
Um thanks for your thoughtful insight.
I'll try to watch everything you appear
on and am much better informed for
seeing it.
If you're a dispensationalist, yes. If
you are
>> explain. So a dispensationalist means
that you follow John Nelson Darby and
and what he laid out with dispensation
dispensations which is like God works
and he works off of a calendar and
there's different dispensations of time.
And that before Jesus can come back
there's certain things that must be
fulfilled like the temple
the temple must be rebuilt because
that's where the Antichrist is going to
rule from. The Jewish state must be must
be recreated. And these are these are
things that dispensationalists teach.
And that's one of the reasons why
American evangelicals are so
are so much in bed with Israel cuz they
think that for Jesus to come back this
has to happen.
Uh
as a as a Christian I can tell you right
now Jesus does not need your help. He
will come back when he's doggone good
and ready and he does not need to come
back because of a a nation
that hates him and teaches that he is
boiling in in semen and
and a crap uh
blows up at mosque. It's [__] I
mean so I mean do you believe these I
mean I do believe these reports. I mean
that
Israel
>> Oh they believe it. Yeah.
I was I mean that's what they want.
They want this to happen and will it
would it unite the Muslim world against
the West? I can't think of anything of
anything greater that would.
Um Paul is asking what do we know about
a bio weapons program? Do they have one?
There's they might but there's no
evidence whatsoever. Um
let's see. Hearing the two of you talk
let's see. Uh some of some suggest that
the US backing the Kurds to fight in
Iran. How do you think this affects
their somewhat autonomous autonomy in
Iraq position in Syria and what would
Turkey think? Um
I think that I think the Kurds are not
going to form a unified front. The Kurds
are divided across the you know these
different borders. They there is you
know obviously they're the same people
but they don't they don't have the same
internal governance.
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah I I think that the the Kurds are a
pawn.
That that's what they are. They they're
there to be moved around and sacrificed.
I don't think anyone has any interest in
helping them set up a state. Turkey's
opposed to it, Iraq is opposed to it.
The Iranians aren't going to give up any
of their territory for it.
And I mean, why would they?
Um let's see. There's some question um
Okay, so all right. There's another
question about that. Um Earthquake in
Iran today, was this a nuclear test?
What happens if Iran nukes Israel? It
was not a nuclear test. That was
probably not
>> Um they're not nearly close enough to
test a nuclear weapon.
Uh that and also Iran is very
seismically active. They get a lot of
earthquakes.
Yeah, well it's that also they're kind
of getting bombed and they're getting
bombed with bunker busters. So I mean
those can definitely trigger some
seismic activity. If you're
>> Yeah, well that's true. And when I was
in Afghanistan, um I was um woken up in
the middle of the night and when my
window broke, a window that had survived
several years of civil war, uh when uh a
bunker buster was used 26 miles away.
And uh the the earth shook. So you were
right about that. There's a seismic
effect at all. Um do we believe the
Adrian wants to know, do we believe that
the Western world can sustain a
protracted Middle Eastern conflict? Uh I
don't see anyone, especially in my Gen Z
generation, looking at a future in the
military.
Would a draft be something you could see
coming back? Speaking personally, I'd
rather be shot or locked in prison than
fight BB's war.
Well,
good good thinking.
Um I don't think a draft is coming back.
I mean, you know, the draft was forced
upon the uh US military. They didn't
want it. I mean, sorry, a volunteer
army. They did They wanted to keep the
draft. They went out kicking and
screaming. Now they would never want the
draft back because the volunteer army is
great for them. Uh you know, people who
they're not having like people like me
aren't having our kids drafted and sent
to wars we disapprove of. The only
people who are going are volunteers. And
so there there's a higher level of
enthusiasm or at least passivity. Well,
you're a student of history. I mean,
remind me, Ted, when when was the first
draft in the United States initiated and
which president initiated it and what
happened in New York City when he did?
Uh that would be Abraham Lincoln, your
favorite president. And half the city
burned down in the draft riots. So was
it 1862? I want to say.
>> 1863. It was So I mean let's not pretend
that the government actually gives a
crap about what we want. If this war
gets big enough, yeah, there'll be a
draft. And and our kids will be ones
paying the price for the ineptitude of
our government.
Uh so um what role should India play in
this conflict?
Stay out.
That always wise.
Um
was Ali Reza Arafi selected on this
from um and then killed requiring
another selection that yielded Mojtaba
Khamenei or was Ali Reza Arafi
disregarded entirely? Or if so, why
would the Assembly of Experts ignore Ali
Khamenei's wishes against his son being
selected?
Um you know, it's impossible to know
these deliberations. They're I mean, the
Assembly of Experts
building was bombed by the Americans,
right? So
they're in chaos over there.
It's I think I I think maybe one day
we'll find out.
Um
Yeah.
>> Um
do we think this bad war could
eventually cause Democrats or
Republicans to finally grow some balls
and stand up to Israel in the future?
Yes. I hope so. Um Gavin Newsom of all
people um just yesterday made some news
by saying that he could see cutting off
all aid and financial assistance to
Israel under a new some presidency.
I would vote for him just for that. And
I just and you know my politics, Ted.
You know my You know my politics. I
would vote Listen, I would vote for
anyone on the promise
of telling Israel to piss off.
That's enough for me at this point.
That's enough. Here's a good question
from
Jimmy.
How closely do the decisions of
Netanyahu and his administration
represent the Israeli population?
Um
closer than it should, right? I mean,
like when I went to Israel the first
time in the '90s,
um it was a country that was like a good
half of the population or a little more,
they were, you know, they they were
liberals. They wanted to live side by
side in peace with the Palestinians in
their own Palestinian state. Um
those people are gone now. They've been
radicalized or they've left the country.
They're like 5% of the country. Um
everybody else, they're all I mean, if
you can even see the anti-war
protests, the anti-Netanyahu protests,
they were complaining that Netanyahu
wasn't doing enough to get the hostages
back. They were not complaining about
the way the Palestinians were being
treated in the apartheid state. Um the
Israeli people are highly Netanyahu
tolerant or I I would say, uh if not
fully in agreement with him these days.
I I have a question for you, Ted,
because you've been there, I haven't. I
just don't know.
Has the right-wing shift in Israeli
politics has that largely been
influenced by all of the Russians and
Ukrainians uh who went to Israel back
in the '90s and the early 2000s? Like
did they push Israeli politics to the
right through demographic change and
I mean,
is that what happened? I think that's
part of it, but not maybe not all of it.
I mean, I think what really happened was
that the right-wingers kind of won the
argument by, you know, they by building
the security wall, right? Once they
built that wall, sort of there used to
be like in the in the '90s to board a
bus in Jerusalem was to take your life
into your own hands. You never knew if
it was going to arrive without being
blown up. You want you know, you want to
pop into a cafe to get in Tel Aviv to
get a latte, you didn't know if you were
coming out. Um they built that [__]
wall and um and they basically, you
know, created the apartheid state
full-on and it really greatly reduced
the number of PLO attacks in Israel. Um
I hate that it worked uh not to say that
I'm pro-terrorism, but the point is this
proved effective in terms of the right
said but you know, the right was like we
kept you safer. Let us do our thing and
people love safety, I think more than
anything else. They care about their own
personal safety more than they care
about justice for other people,
especially people from a different
ethnic group.
Yeah, I could see it and uh just to
reply to a comment that Robbie is gay.
Listen, I am the gayest person you're
ever going to meet. I am happy. I'm one
of the happiest people you're ever going
to find in your life. So uh that's not
an insult. I am I I am as gay as you
could possibly be in the old-school
[snorts] traditional uh definition of
that word. Very happy. Three minutes
left. Let's do a few more questions and
Robbie, thanks thanks for filling in for
John. Um Clay Dellinger, to young
Americans who feel like they're starting
to wake up to the complexities of
foreign affairs and the corruption at
home, is there specific advice you would
give uh external news sources seem like
a start. 100%. Yeah. Um external news
sources are definitely a good start.
Yeah, uh question everything. Uh verify,
verify, verify. And if you're especially
feeling social media
>> Like when we had Akilies Luria on
earlier and people were like, "Wait, do
you guys have any financial ties with
him?" That's a good [__] question and
you should be asking questions like
that. 100% and that's not a bad thing.
Questions are not bad.
Uh
what one thing that I would
that I would recommend that that you
look for
is if you're seeing all the big
influencers and they are all saying the
same thing Yeah. They're they're getting
they're getting talking points from
someone.
Yes.
It's a good idea to balance things out
with people who you agree with and
people who you disagree with.
That way you won't fall victim to your
own confirmation bias. I'm a right
winger. It'd be very easy for me
to just surround myself with right-wing
influencers.
Conversely, two of my two of my best
friends are lefties.
It's a very good thing to have your feet
firmly in both camps and don't be afraid
to ask questions and learn and admit
that you're wrong. 100%. Uh Goon7956,
was the Iranian girl school really hit?
Yes, it was and you're going to say,
"Ted, how do you know?" The reason I
know is because there's no question
about there's the people who are best
situated to oppose it, to say that this
was a false flag, that the Iranians did
it themselves, or that it didn't happen
aren't saying that. The There's no
denials coming from the US or Israel
Israeli government saying that this
didn't happen. That those denials
wouldn't mean that it didn't happen, but
when there's no denials everybody's on
the same page, yeah, it happened.
Yeah.
Um
How long do you think the UAE, Saudis,
Bahrain, Qatar, and Oman will keep
accepting getting attacked by Iran and
getting their economies hurt? There's
There's back channel calls right
happening right now between the Trump
administration and those countries and
they're trying to decide like, you know,
you know, whether they should or can get
involved, those countries have a
problem. They uh oppose Iran on behalf
of Israel, but their their people don't.
And so, they have to That's the needle
they have to thread.
Yeah, I agree with that.
And monarchies, contrary to popular
belief, even the monarchies,
dictatorships,
They care about public opinion. Well,
because if they don't, their heads end
up on spikes. Uh
That That's happened to the French.
>> Even Nazi Germany, they used to have uh
Hitler had spies in cafes and bars all
over Germany to find out what people
were really thinking. Even if if if
Adolf Hitler had to care, everybody's
got to care. Everyone, thanks so much
for joining us. Thanks for watching the
program with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
9:00 a.m. Eastern time, Monday through
Friday. John was out today. Robbie
Weston was filling in. Thank you so
much. Thank you, Achilles Larrea. Thanks
everyone for your support. Please stay
tuned. We'll be back tomorrow. John will
be back. Uh please stay tuned for the
TMI show with me and Mel O'Malley Chan,
and Robbie will be there, too. Take
care, all.
And uh oh,
and
uh let's see.
Uh how are we going to do this? Oh,
yeah. Here we go.
>> [music]